

SHERIF OSAMA KHODEIR

153, Beverly Hills, Sheikh Zayed, 6 October, Giza, Egypt

Phone: +2 012-0303-9163 || Email: sheriff.koder@hotmail.com

Summary

Electrical Engineer have been working in customer focused jobs for about 7 years, at this time working on my technical skills and looking for opportunities to work in more technical related positions where I can combine my passion and interest for technology and my gained interpersonal skills as I still have desire, capacity to learn, work and grow.

Highlights

	Strategic	thinking	and n	lanning
_	Strategic	UIIIIKIIIR	allu p	Idillillig

- Goal oriented
- Sales process
- Excellent interpersonal and time management skills.
- Customer benefit and value focused

- Written and Verbal Communication skills
- Presentation skills
- Phone skills
- Work ethics
- Quickly gain extensive knowledge of products

- Fluent English language
- Software development
- Hardware design
- Microsoft Office
- Surveys and Analysis

Education

Bachelor in Engineering

February 2015

Faculty of Engineering, Electrical Communication and Electronics Department

Modern Sciences and Arts (MSA) University

(Third class Honors)

(Grade: Good)

• University of Greenwich (Bachelor of science)

• Graduation Project: Design and Implementation of a Wireless Data-Show Adaptor (Very Good)

Dream International School June 2009

Narmer Language School

Experience

Senior Property Consultant

June 2021 to December 2022

June 2006

Manazel Real Estate

- Private business opened as a partnership with colleagues
- Working as part of the sales team to develop both new and existing markets.
- Find new properties that would add to the company's inventory
- Daily reviewing, prospecting and qualifying clients from different sources and leading them to further steps in the sale by using strategic selling.

Senior Property Consultant

July 2020 to June 2021

ORASCOM Developments

- Promote the company's varied range of coastal residential projects to new or existing clients
- Find new sub real estate agencies to work with our company to reach new clients
- Make presentations in our office or the agency's office to their sales employees and handle their enquiries

Property Consultant

November 2017 to July 2020

Coldwell Banker New Homes

- Utilized strong analytical and problem-solving techniques in order to deliver the correct products to their respective clients that match their needs.
- Take appointments to meet new and existing clients.
- Market, competition and inventory study and survey
- Recognized as employee of the month only after 4 months of working
- Frequently closed deals that served to increase the company share
- Putting daily goals and achieve them to get closer to weekly and monthly goals

Property Consultant

November 2016 to November 2017

Units Real Estate

- Presentation, communication and selling skills development
- Approaching new clients from our booths at different events

• Daily pipeline management and incoming lead qualification

Customer Care Advisor

November 2015 to July 2016

Vodafone UK

- Enhanced English Language, excellent telephone manner and listening skills.
- Responsible for UK Accounts
- Handling customer queries on the phone or after the shift
- Maintained our company's image and build rapport while handling fatal customer issues
- Maintained Daily KPIs targets

Training

Advanced Selling skills and Techniques Part II " by Coldwell Banker

December 2018

post-selling consolidation, Building Value, Introduction to Negotiation techniques

Advanced Selling skills and Techniques Part I " by Coldwell Banker

July 2018

Sales process, buying steps, selling techniques

Enhanced Embedded Systems "by Embedded Fab

September 2016

- Learnt and Practiced programming languages like C++, Assembly
- Different Software development methods (Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, V)
- Hardware Design and Software Management of a Team-Based Project "ID Entry Controller and Register for Building Access"
- Basics of Mobile Telecommunication & LTE Advanced "by SYSTEL Motorola July 2015